Dad.
爸
I'm at the airport.
我在机场
My dad is here.
我爸在这儿呢
Your legendary dad?
传说中的伯父啊
Come with me.
你跟我一起过去吧
If you are around too,
你在的话
he would let me go earlier.
他能早点放我走
What should I say
我一会儿见了你爸
when I see your day?
说什么呀
Just sit far away
你就远远地坐着
and pretend that
就装作一副
you're in a hurry to catch the plane.
着急赶飞机的样子
Go.
去
Xiao.
晓晓
This is my colleague, Duan Rou.
这是我同事段柔
Hello, uncle.
叔叔好
Hello.
你好
You guys go ahead,
那你们先聊
I'll wait over there.
我去旁边等着
Have a seat.
坐吧
You're on a business trip?
您出差啊
I'm attending a conference in Sanya.
去三亚开个论坛会
Where are you going?
你去哪儿
I’m going to Anhui
我去安徽
for an alternative energy project.
一个新能源的项目
Alternative energy has been
这两年新能源
on the rise in recent years.
势头比较大
The direction you chose is good.
你选的这个方向不错
Do you...
最近
have any plans to purchase an apartment?
有没有买房子的计划
I can provide you with some monetary aid.
爸爸可以补贴你
No.
不买
The loft I rent is enough for me.
我租的复式够用了
My company gives subsidies for rent too.
单位还有租房补贴
Move into somewhere with a better location.
换一个好一点的地段
I can help you with the rent.
爸爸可以补贴你
No need.
不用
The place I'm staying at is good enough.
我住那边已经很好了
It's near to my office too.
离公司也方便
Right.
是啊
It's close to your office.
离公司近
You've used
你那车
your car for a few years now, right?
也开了好几年了吧
Why not get a new one?
要不换一台
I have already
我最近
bought a new car recently.
已经买了一辆新的了
I drive both my new car and my old car interchangeably.
和以前那辆换着开
Good.
好
Take me away.
带我走
Hello?
喂
Yes.
是
We're together.
我们在一块儿呢
Sure, sure.
好 好
You have a phone call, Gui Xiao.
电话 归晓
Now?
现在
It's urgent.
着急
Hello? Give me a moment.
喂 您稍等
Dad, I have to tend to this.
那个爸 我这儿有点事
I'll go first
我就先走了
and board the plane directly afterwards.
一会儿我直接登机了
Goodbye, uncle.
叔叔再见
Go ahead.
您说 您说
Why do you always want to run away when you see your dad?
你见你爸怎么总想逃啊
I have nothing to say.
没话说
What were you talking about?
那刚聊什么呢
It was as serious as a meeting.
严肃得跟开会一样
He wants to buy me a car and a house.
他想给我买车买房
I said I don't need it. I have them.
我说不需要 我自己有
Who would think they have too many houses and cars?
房子和车子可不嫌多啊
I can earn it myself.
我自己能挣
I don't need him.
不需要他的
We're not boarding till a little later,
一会儿才登机呢
why turn off your phone now?
现在关机干吗
I need to read this thick stack
我这一摞资料文件
of documents.
要看呢
I'm more at peace with my phone turned off.
关了机清净
Besides,
再说了
if there's anything urgent, they'd look for you.
有急事找你呗
What if your boyfriend contacts you?
不怕男朋友找啊
He can't use communication devices
他这段时间都是
during this period of time.
禁止使用移动通讯设备
He can only contact me
想要找我
through psychic powers.
那只能用意念
What is he doing?
干什么去了
It's a secret.
保密的
My sister is a SWAT.
我姐就是特警
My family would never asked her about it
家里人从来不会问她
and she never told us either.
她从来也不说
As long as it's related to work,
只要跟工作有关的事
she can't talk about it.
都不能说
She can't say what mission it is.
什么任务不能说
She can't say when she will be back.
什么时候回来不能说
She can't even talk about when she
什么时候受伤了
injured herself or
什么时候立功了
when she made an achievement.
都不能说
In any case, she'd just say,
总之有事就一句
"I have a mission,"
有任务
and leave immediately.
立刻就得走
Nameless Hero
无名英雄
and their family members.
及英雄家属
Attention!
立正
At ease.
跨立
It's a new year.
新年新气象
Everyone seem to
大家的气色
look good.
看起来都不错
This Chinese New Year,
这个春节呢
Captain Lin and I have come together
我和林队协同合作
to bring you a big gift.
为大家带来了一份大礼
This gift
这份大礼呢
is a competition with
就是跟张冶市特警队
with Zhangyan SWAT.
进行一场大比武
Thank you, Captain Lu.
谢谢路队
Thank you, Captain Lin.
谢谢林队
First Squadron, Second Squadron will participate in the competition.
一中队 二中队参加比武
All new members will observe.
所有的新成员全程观摩
Sir.
报告
Go ahead.
讲
When does it start?
什么时候开始
Tomorrow.
明天
The competition is divided into four major parts.
这次比武分为四大部分
Comprehensive skills test includes
综合技能测试
five kilometer run, crawling,
包括负重五公里
climbing, and sliding, with weights.
匍匐 攀登 下滑
Driving test includes
驾驶测试
driving the bomb squad vehicle
包括防爆车
and the 13.5 ton armored vehicle.
十三点五吨装甲车驾驶
Shooting test includes
射击测试
shooting with shotgun,
包括长短枪应用射击
as well as
以及狙击枪的
side shooting,
翻转枪面射击
territory snatching shooting,
抢占阵地射击
and shooting while running with a sniper.
奔袭射击
Finally it's the individual combat.
最后是个人搏击
Which includes language test
语言测试
and drones operation.
和无人机操作
Let me emphasize one point.
强调一点
Captain Lu and I are the
我和路队是本次
conductor of the language test.
语言测试的主考官
Bring it on
大家有什么
if you are skilled in
小语种的本事
any minority language.
尽管拿出来
Captain Lu can understand it all.
路队全听得懂
For a mission, Captain Lu
当初路队为了出任务
mastered three languages
可是两年就拿下了
in two years.
三门语言
As for the rest,
还有剩下的
they will be on-site judgment and mental strength,
现场判断 心理素质
which will be evaluated
都在明天的
during the combat practice tomorrow.
实战练习里评估
Any questions?
还有什么问题吗
Sir.
报告
Speak.
说
Will Captain Lu be joining too?
路队也参加吗
Of course.
当然
As the captain,
既然是队长
you should perform better than us.
就要比我们好
Of course.
当然
Go!
冲
Okay, go.
好 走
The visibility is good.
可视条件不错
I almost can't see the target.
快看不见靶子了
Captain Lu hit all the targets.
路队全中
Captain Du missed one.
杜队漏一
Our team's gun champion has been overtaken.
我们队的枪王要换人了
I concede.
心服口服
Captain Lu.
路队
Why did you choose the bomb squad?
为什么选排爆
Because
因为
it's more dangerous.
更危险
Someone has to do it.
总是要有人做
Right?
不是吗
What about you?
你呢
Me?
我
I studied security management at the Police Academy.
我警校学的治安管理
After my internship following my graduation,
毕业以后实习
I was being assigned.
然后直接分配
My leader asked me to choose.
我们领导让我自己选
I said,
我说
I'll do as you say.
一切服从安排
Good boy.
好孩子
It's been a while since I first started.
真是一干很多年
I just graduated then.
我那时候才刚毕业
We had 40 classmates.
我们同期四十个人
One of them had sacrificed.
现在有一个已经牺牲了
There are also three who are severely injured and disabled.
还有三个重伤残疾
Do you have any more?
还有吗
Yes.
有
Follow me to the meeting room
跟我去会议室
and write the evaluation report.
写评估报告
I'll make sure you'll have enough.
管够
Rise.
起立
Captain.
支队长
Where's Captain Lu?
你们路队呢
As usual,
队里的老规矩
whoever has the highest position will go first.
谁的官职最大谁先上
Who made this bomb?
这个炸弹是谁做的
Me.
我呀
I'm good at it.
我手艺可好了
I heard
听说
you often exchange gifts.
你们俩经常交换礼物
Before I met Captain Lu, I've never met anyone
路队来前我没有遇到过
who was better at making bombs than me.
做炸弹比我好的人
I finally met a rival.
这次终于棋逢对手了
I can't waste my chance.
我肯定不能浪费机会
We are simulating real cases
我们模拟的全部都是
that happened both domestically and internationally.
国内外的真实案例
They are not planned scenarios
并不是假设
but actual cases bomb disposal experts
而是曾有排爆专家
have faced.
面对过的
This bomb is strong enough
这个爆炸装置的当量
to make sure no one at the scene can survive.
足以使现场无人生还
Command Center.
指挥中心
The explosive has been triggered.
爆炸物处于待激发状态
It can't be moved anymore.
不能再移动
Given the conditions here,
现场条件
we won't be able to dispose it with machinery.
不允许机械作业
I will be disposing it manually.
准备人工作业
Be careful.
注意安全
Everyone, evacuate from the center.
所有人员撤离中心现场
Before coming to the team,
没来大队之前
I thought it was all about cutting wires.
我还以为都是剪线
Just guess which one to cut.
猜出剪哪根就好了
It's not that easy.
哪有那么容易啊
The bomb you're met with
你们每次
every time will be different.
遇到的爆炸装置都不同
The conditions of the scene will be different too.
每次的现场也都不同
The only similarity is
唯一相同的是
you have no chance to fail.
你们没有失败的机会
Your first failure
你的第一次失手
will also be your last.
就是最后一次
The explosion device has been disposed successfully.
起爆装置成功拆除
Zhou Xin.
周鑫
Now it's your turn
现在要考校你
to operate the robot
操作机器人
to move the bomb.
转移炸弹
Roger.
收到
The bomb has been disposed.
炸弹解除完毕
It's as if it were real.
跟真的一样
I'm so nervous that I'm sweating.
紧张到我都出汗了
It is real.
本来就是真的
This is a bomb
这就是路队
Captain Lu has once disposed.
拆过的一次现场
It is a real life simulation.
他给你们一比一还原的
The only difference is, the bomb today
唯一不同的是爆炸装置
was made by me.
今天的是我做的
It's more complex
比歹徒做的更难
and dangerous.
也更危险
Sorry.
对不起啊
I'm late.
来晚了
Guess what I did yesterday.
你猜我昨天干吗去了
Drinking.
喝酒
How did you know?
你怎么知道
The finance team came to me just now,
财务刚才来找我了
asking me why
问我为什么
your recent reimbursements
你最近的报销单
are all drinking expenses.
全是喝酒的
I told him
我跟他说
you're going to get
你快要拿下一个
a blind box project.
盲盒的项目了
If this continues,
再这么谈下去
I'm going to open a blind box store myself.
我都想开盲盒店了
I didn't expect
真没想到
blind boxes to become so trendy
这两年盲盒
over the past two years.
能一下子起来
You can't even invest in it even if you have money.
拿着钱都投不进去
Work hard in the next round.
下一轮努力呗
I have another
我还有个
due diligence I have to do for a education platform.
教育平台的尽调呢
Education is easy.
教育好做呀
It's the easiest to get contacts in.
最好接触了
You seem to be very interested
我发现你对小孩的事
in things about kids.
好像很感兴趣
I like kids.
我喜欢小孩啊
You're back.
回来了
How's your due diligence?
尽调怎么样
I just finished talking with my client.
刚跟客户聊完
It went well.
进展顺利
I was afraid you wouldn't have time
我啊还怕你没时间
to have a meeting with us.
跟我们开会呢
I have time.
有时间
As long as I'm awake,
只要我醒着
it's working time.
都是工作时间
Go ahead.
说吧
It's a call from Qining.
齐宁打过来的
Hello?
喂
Lu,
老路
I saw the note you left.
我看你的留言了
I just came back.
刚回来
I'm telling you,
和你说
there has been to many missions lately.
最近任务太多了
My household register is still at home.
户口本还在家里
I don't have time to pick it up.
没时间回去取
The school year is about to start.
孩子快开学了
Yes, I know.
是 我知道
I’ll discuss it with his mother.
我再和他妈妈商量一下
It’s Lu Yanchen's call?
是路炎晨电话
Tell him
告诉他
his transfer procedure isn't completed yet.
他调动手续还没办完
Ask him to come over when he's free.
抽空让他过来一趟
Okay, I'll tell him now.
好 我这就跟他说
Did you hear that?
你都听见了吧
Come back soon.
抓紧回来吧
When you come back this time,
这次回来呀
you might meet
说不定能见到
the person you've been wanting to see.
你想见到的人
There's a clue?
有线索了
Fortunately, your transfer procedure is not complete yet.
幸亏你的关系还没转完
So you're still considered to be under Qining.
还算咱们齐宁的人
It used to be a case you handled.
从前是你接手的案子
You have to complete the handover.
你得交接完了
Come back.
回来吧
It's almost at the end.
快尘埃落定了
I'll arrange it as soon as possible.
我尽快安排
Okay.
好
Captain.
支队长
I'm informing you,
跟你通知一下
Captain Lu is on leave
你们路队放个假
to make a trip back to Qining.
回一趟齐宁
You'd have to take on more responsibilities for the work here.
这儿的工作你要多担着
I heard about it.
我听说了
I saw his ex-colleague that day.
那天见到他原来的同事
He said he never took a day off
说他从进警队
since he joined the police force.
一天私人假都没请过
I guess something urgent came up
这次回齐宁
for him to return to Qining this time.
估计是有什么要紧事吧
They've found some clues
一桩旧事
for an old case.
已经有眉目了
Thank you for your hard work.
大家辛苦了
Boss, you saying this
老板 你说这种话
make me feel like I have to work overtime today.
我感觉今天要加班了啊
That's up to you.
想加班随便你啊
Mr. Sun.
孙老师
I'm free.
我方便 我方便
Okay, thank you.
好的 好的 麻烦您了
Bye.
再见
I won't have dinner
一会儿我就不跟你们
with you all later.
一起去吃饭了
You're going home, right?
你不是要回家吗
Take me with you.
带我一程
I didn't drive today.
我今儿没开车
We're going in the same direction.
正好一个方向
Okay.
好
Bye. Bye.
再见 再见 再见
Here.
来
Eat more.
多吃点啊
How long were you
你今天一个人
standing alone
在学校门口
by the school gate today?
站了多久啊
Not long. I thought about it.
没多久 我想好了
If no one comes by the time night falls,
晚上等不到
I'll sleep in the classroom.
我回教室睡觉
What are you talking about?
瞎说什么呢
You should've called me.
给我打电话呀
Why didn't you call me?
干吗不找我
It's fine.
真没事
Sorry, Nan.
对不起 小楠
I'm really sorry.
真是不好意思
There was an accident on the road
我呢路上有车追尾了
so I was stuck in traffic.
一直堵着
Your house is far away.
你们家离得远
What time
你平时
do you normally send him to school?
你都几点送他上学啊
If I send him,
我要送他的话
it's at 5 a.m.
也就早上五点吧
Otherwise, there must be traffic jam.
要不然肯定堵车
He'll be late.
必迟到
But it was
但是这都是
Lu Chen who asked me for this favor.
路晨交代我的
I have to help my brother.
为兄弟两肋插刀
It doesn't matter.
这无所谓
For him,
我现在为了他啊
I don't even drink alcohol anymore.
我酒都不敢喝了
I have to be his driver.
我得给他当司机
Oh right,
对了
look at this screenshot.
你看这截图
Lu Chen sent it to me.
这路晨发给我的
This is the homework left by the teacher.
这是老师留的作业
They get homework assigned online now?
现在都在网上布置作业
Yes.
对啊
Nowadays,
现在是
you can see what homework
你下个软件一点开
the teacher has assigned
就能看见老师
when you click into an app you download.
布置什么作业了
Look.
你看
Today's Chinese homework
今天这语文作业
is reciting.
是阅读朗诵
Math homework is calculation.
数学作业是口算
These are simple.
这都简单
But I'm really not good at English.
主要这英文啊我真不行
How about this?
要不这样吧
Leave Qin Xiaonan to me this week.
这周就把秦小楠交给我
He can stay at my place.
住我家
I'm not going on a business trip either.
正好我也不出差
I'll be home from Monday to Friday.
周一至周五我都在家
I can even help him with his homework.
我还能帮他看作业
Is that appropriate?
这合适吗
Why not?
有什么不合适的
He stayed at my place
他刚来北京
when he first came to Beijing.
不就住我家吗
Thank you so much then.
那 那太谢谢了 谢谢
Thank you, family.
亲人啊 谢谢
Eat up. It's on you.
快吃吧 你请
Sure.
行
Ask me if you have any questions.
有问题就问
At your age,
你这个年纪
you should keep asking questions.
就该不停地提问
Aunt Gui Xiao, what are you reading?
归晓阿姨 你在看什么
I'm reading a financial report.
我在看财务报表
I have to monitor the operations
我投的项目每个月
of projects I invested in every month
都要看它的运营状况
through this.
要看这个
What about Aunt Duan Rou?
段柔阿姨呢
I'm watching "The Good Dinosaur."
我在看恐龙小当家
Be serious.
你好好说
I'm looking at a nursing home's introduction.
我在看养老公寓的介绍
My friend's mother
我朋友的妈妈
wants to move to a nursing home lately.
最近想要住养老公寓
I found that this is
我发现这是一个
a very promising project.
前景非常不错的项目
So I'm going to invest.
所以准备投一下
Have we fed your curiosity yet?
满足求知欲了吗
I'll continue with
我继续写
my Chinese homework.
我的语文作业了
Take whatever you want.
要喝什么自己拿
If you talk about such professional things with a kid,
你和小孩说那么专业
he won't be able to understand.
他也听不懂啊
This is how my mum
我从小我妈
talked to me since I was a kid.
就是这么跟我说话的
She never gloss over her words.
从来不敷衍
She answers
我问什么
whatever I ask.
她就系统答什么
I think it's good.
我觉得这样挺好的
It made me feel like this world is amazing
让我从小就觉得
since I was young,
这个世界很神奇
and I have to study hard
得好好学习
so that I can have a good job.
才能工作爽一把
Your mother taught you so well.
还是阿姨教导有方
Sleep with me tonight.
晚上跟我睡
I'll sleep with Xiaonan.
我跟小楠睡
Qin Xiaonan told me secretly that
秦小楠悄悄跟我说
every time he stays at your place,
他每次住在你家
he doesn't dare to go to the toilet at midnight.
半夜都不敢上厕所
Your house is too big.
你家太大了
I promised to sleep with him.
我答应陪他睡
I'll turn the light on for him at night,
半夜给他开灯
He never told me about that.
他从来没有跟我说过
You are the host,
你是主人
he's a child. He's too shy to say it.
小孩子懂事不好意思说
This kid.
这小孩
But he's not shy to talk about it with another guest?
跟客人还好意思说
Yes.
是啊
Fine, it's a double bed anyway.
行 反正是双人床
How are you and your ex-boyfriend?
你和你前男友怎么样了
We're getting along.
关系缓和
We're friends.
朋友
Is he single?
他单身吗
Kind of.
目前算是吧
What about in the past?
那以前呢
It was a little complicated.
稍许复杂
Son.
儿子
Are you up?
起床了吗
Did you do your homework last night?
昨晚作业做了吗
How is the new campus?
新校区怎么样
Do you have enough money?
钱够花吗
I'm sorry.
不好意思啊
Your son went out.
你儿子出去了
I answered his call in a daze.
我睡糊涂接了他的电话
You are...
请问你是
I'm a colleague of Gui Xiao.
我是归晓的同事
I'm helping her take care of your kid.
帮你带儿子
I'm so grate...
那实在是太
Don't stand on ceremony.
不用不好意思
I like him.
我喜欢他
Thank you.
谢谢啊
You're welcome.
不客气
Nan.
小楠
I'll ask him to call you back later.
我一会儿让他回给你吧
Okay.
好
Bye.
再见
Have some hot food.
来两口热乎的
It's too late for lamb soup.
羊汤来不及喝了
The meeting is starting.
马上开会了
How's your son dealing with his school transfer?
儿子转学还习惯吗
I don't know.
不知道啊
You called him for so long, you didn't ask?
那你刚打半天电话没问
My son didn't answer the call.
刚才不是我儿子接的
It's Captain Lu's
是路队
ex-girlfriend's colleague who picked it up.
前女友的同事接的
Hello. It's Lu Yanchen.
喂 你好 路炎晨
Lu.
老路
My son
我儿子
is still at your ex's house?
还在你前女友家呢
I don't think it's appropriate.
不太好意思吧
My friend's taking care of him.
给我朋友带呢
Impossible.
不可能
I just called him.
我刚打完电话
Gui Xiao's colleague picked it up.
归晓的同事接的
You haven't been home these days?
你这几天没回家
Yes.
对
Turn on your phone.
你这样 快开机
Buy Gui Xiao a meal for me.
替我请归晓吃个饭
I feel bad.
心里过意不去
Get in the car and wait.
上车等着
Are you off work?
下班了
Not yet.
还没呢
I'm off work.
我下班了
I'll show Nan around
我带小楠去逛逛
and wait for you nearby.
在附近等你
But I still have a while to go.
可我还要好久呢
I'm off work.
我已经下班了
I'll wait no matter how late it is.
多晚都等
You can't do that.
那不行
He has homework to do.
他还要写作业呢
I'll find a place to get a glass of water
我找个地方买杯水
and take him to do homework.
带他做作业
No.
不可以
He can't focus on his homework this way.
这样他做作业不专心
It's not good for him.
会带坏小孩的
I didn't realize
过去没发现
that you're quite experienced in taking care of children.
你照顾孩子还挺有经验
you could take care of a child alone.
你还能单独带小孩
I'll wait for you.
我等你
Nan knows my place better than you do.
我家小楠比你熟
Go ahead.
去吧
By myself?
我自己去
It's for Xiaonan to do his homework.
是给他写作业用的
It's on the sake of Xiaonan.
看在小楠的面子上
Change into these.
换吧
What do you want to drink? I'll get it for you.
你想喝什么我去给你倒
Get lost.
滚蛋
Is this your home?
这是你家啊
Being all hospitable.
还客气上了
I'm going to go do my homework if you don't want anything to drink.
你不喝水我去做作业了
Go.
去吧
Don't touch
不要乱动
Aunt Gui Xiao's things.
归晓阿姨的东西
She doesn't like it.
她不喜欢
Go do your homework.
写作业去
I bought you takeout.
我给你们买了外卖
What a waste.
浪费了
No.
不浪费
We'll take it back and eat it at home.
我们两个带回去吃
I'll heat it up for you.
给你热
♫And the fallen leaves of autumn♫
我帮你
No need. Just wait.
不用 等着吃
This is his homework this week.
这是他这周的作业
I've sorted them according
我已经分门别类
to their subjects.
都理好了
The post-its on it
上边的便签纸
also says what he has to do.
也写上了具体要做什么
I'm a master of self-care？
我是自理小达人
He needs to
就是他要整理
pack his own bag,
自己的书包
bed, and wardrobe.
床铺还有衣柜
When he's done packing them,
整理好了
give him a star
你就给他打个五角星
and have him hand it in to the teacher.
交给老师就可以了
The education system nowadays
现在的小朋友读书
is indeed different from what we had.
和我们过去确实不一样
Yes, it's very meticulous.
是 可精细了
Bye.
走了
I'm on break this week.
我这个星期正常休息
If you're free,
你要是有空的话
feel free to look for me.
随时找我
Let's go.
走了
Goodbye, Aunt Gui Xiao.
归晓阿姨再见
Do you want to go back with us?
想不想和我们回去玩
Now?
现在
I can drive back.
我正好开车回去
What I mean is,
我的意思
I can take you there,
带你过去
and you can live
你正好可以住
at Meng Xiaoshan's house
孟小杉家里
and have a catch up with her.
和她聚聚
Go pack your things.
还不快去收拾东西
Give me ten minutes.
等我十分钟
I haven't been back for a long time.
太久没回来了
There's no one to clean this place.
也没有人收拾
It's okay.
没关系
You're back.
回来了
I'll take you home first.
先送你回去
Who is she? Is she your girlfriend?
这是谁啊 女朋友啊
Why can't I see her?
怎么还见不得人哪
Why are you running?
跑什么呀
That's my dad.
那个是我爸
I know.
我知道
Have you seen him?
你见过吗
In the past?
过去
I remember his voice.
我记得他的声音
Brat,
臭小子
do you think this is a hotel?
你把这儿当饭馆了你
Come out!
给我滚出来
Get out!
滚出来
I didn't expect you to remember it for so many years.
没想到你记了这么多年
I wanted to
本来想跟你
spend a nice weekend with you.
好好过一个周末的
I'm sorry.
对不起
We can spend it even without staying here.
不在这儿也能过
You're so boring.
你这人挺没情趣的
We dated in the garage when we were young.
小时候约会就在修理厂
Do we still date here now?
现在还是这儿
Let's go.
走吧
Where are we going?
去哪儿
We can't stay here anyway.
总之不能在这儿
Let's go.
走
It's locked.
这锁了
This is... A master key?
你这是万能钥匙
What are you thinking?
想什么呢
It's just a normal key.
正经钥匙
What does a normal key even mean.
钥匙还分正经不正经
Even if this is
就算是
Meng Xiaoshan's husband's place,
孟小杉她老公的地方
we can't just go in, right?
但咱也不能随便进吧
Qin Feng gave me the key.
秦枫给我的钥匙
He wants me to check the
他想趁着我休假
surveillance equipment here
让我来帮他检查一下
since I'm on break.
这边的监控设备
That's why I have this.
才有了这个
You should have told me earlier.
早说呀
Do you remember where you sat?
你当时坐哪儿还记得吗
By the window.
窗边
You turned in and saw Hai Jianfeng,
你拐进来看见海剑锋
and got off the car to talk to him
下车和他说的话
I knew you could see me coming.
果然能看到我过来
It's quite comfortable.
还挺舒服
Why did you pretend
那天你为什么
not to know me that day?
装着不认识我
It was crowded that day.
那天人多
I was afraid that people would make a fuss.
怕大家起你哄
How many times
你说我们
have we broken up?
闹过几次分手
Not even once.
没闹过
Impossible.
不可能
There are so many times I remember.
我记得的都有好多次
It takes two to break up.
闹是要两个人对着吵
Except for the last time,
除了最后一次
it was always you
每一次都是你
who announced that
单方面地宣布
you've dumped me.
把我给甩了
So it's not called breaking up.
所以不叫闹分手
Fine, fight.
好吧 吵架
A one-sided fight?
单方面吵架
I remember now. The first time was
我想起来了 第一次是
the day we took graduation photos.
拍毕业合照那天
Your classmate made a fuss,
你们班同学起哄你
saying your deskmate has a crush on you.
说你同桌暗恋你
I guess.
算是吧
Why do I still get jealous thinking about it now?
怎么现在想想还吃醋
That's normal.
正常
What do you mean?
什么叫正常啊
What are you doing?
干什么呢
You came
谈恋爱
all the way here to date?
跑人台球厅谈来了
You even broke in.
还撬门
Your boss gave me the key.
你们老板给的我钥匙
That's really his key.
还真是一样的
Who are you?
你谁啊
Lu Chen.
路晨
Are you that bomb disposal expert from Lu family?
你是路家那个排爆专家
A SWAT.
特警
I know. I know.
我知道 我知道
You're a bomb disposal expert.
你拆弹的
Why are you here in the middle of the night?
你大半夜来这儿
Something happened?
有情况
Your boss
你们老板
asked me to check
让我来检查一下
the surveillance system here.
这边的监控系统
He said there were blind spots.
说有死角拍不到
He asked me to adjust
让我来调整一下
the angle of the camera.
摄像头的角度